{
    "id": "c04c63ee57e2459486149027cabc2b35",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I knew ………………………. I had made a mistake.",
            "description": "We use that to introduce a noun clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "as",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. we heard the noise, we ran out of the house.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "As soon as",
                "As long as",
                "As much as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He worked hard ………………………….. he could earn enough to make a living.",
            "description": "So that shows purpose. ",
            "answers": [
                "so as to",
                "so that",
                "in order to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. I get a day off, I will visit my parents.",
            "description": "We use if to express a condition. ",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He died in the town ………………………….. he was born.",
            "description": "We can use where to introduce adverb clauses of place.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "where",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. the soldiers were poorly armed, they offered a stubborn resistance.",
            "description": "We use although and though to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "Though",
                "However",
                "Despite"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He spends more ………………………….. he earns.",
            "description": "We use than after a comparative expression.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "then"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. you mend your ways, you will land in trouble.",
            "description": "Unless is similar to if not.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Unless",
                "Until"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… you work conscientiously, you will achieve success.",
            "description": "Unless is similar to if not.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Unless"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The washing machine ………………………… I bought yesterday is energy efficient.",
            "description": "Both which and that can refer to objects in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "what",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Work hard ……………………………. you will succeed.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "for",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He went home …………………………… he was bored.",
            "description": "Because gives the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "so",
                "thus"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}